Many of you here have probably heard of the 10,000 hours rule.
你们很多人可能都听说过“一万小时定律”。
It's the idea that to become great in anything takes 10,000 hours of focused practice,
这个定律认为，要在任何领域取得卓越成就，需要一万小时的专注练习，
so you'd better get started as early as possible.
所以你最好尽早开始。
The poster child for this story is Tiger Woods.
这个故事的典型代表是泰格·伍兹。
His father famously gave him a putter when he was seven months old.
他的父亲在他七个月大的时候就给了他一支推杆，这很有名。
Fast forward to the age of 21, he's the greatest golfer in the world.
快进到21岁，他成为了世界上最伟大的高尔夫球手。
It's a quintessential 10,000 hours story.
这是一个典型的“一万小时定律”的故事。
Another is that of the three Polger sisters,
另一个是波尔加三姐妹的故事，
whose father decided to teach them chess in a very technical manner from a very early age.
她们的父亲决定从小就以非常专业的方式教她们下棋。
Two of his daughters went on to become grandmaster chess players.
他的两个女儿后来都成为了国际象棋特级大师。
I got curious.
我开始好奇。
If this 10,000 hours rule is correct,
如果这个“一万小时定律”是正确的，
then we should see that elite athletes get a head start in so-called deliberate practice.
那么我们应该看到精英运动员在所谓的“刻意练习”中占得先机。
And in fact, when scientists study elite athletes,
事实上，当科学家研究精英运动员时，
they see that they spend more time in deliberate practice.
他们发现这些运动员确实在刻意练习上花费了更多时间。
Not a big surprise.
这并不令人惊讶。
When they actually track athletes over the course of their development,
当他们实际追踪运动员的发展历程时，
the pattern looks like this.
模式是这样的。
The future elites tend to have what scientists call a sampling period,
未来的精英们往往会经历科学家所说的“采样期”，
where they try a variety of physical activities,
在这个时期，他们会尝试各种体育活动，
they gain broad general skills,
获得广泛的通用技能，
and delay specializing until later than peers who plateau at lower levels.
并且比那些停滞在较低水平的同龄人更晚才开始专精。
That doesn't really comport with the 10,000 hours rule, does it?
这似乎与“一万小时定律”不太相符，不是吗？
So I started to wonder about other domains that we associate with obligatory early specialization,
所以我开始思考其他我们认为必须早期专业化的领域，
like music.
比如音乐。
Turns out the pattern's often similar.
结果发现模式通常是相似的。
The exceptional musicians didn't start spending more time in deliberate practice
杰出的音乐家直到他们的第三种乐器，才开始比普通音乐家投入更多时间进行刻意练习。
than the average musicians until their third instrument.
他们也倾向于有一个“采样期”。
They, too, tended to have a sampling period.
即使是我们认为天赋异禀的音乐家，比如马友友。
Even musicians we think of as famously precocious, like Yo-Yo Ma.
这让我对那些我长期以来钦佩的人的发展背景产生了兴趣。
So this got me interested in exploring the developmental backgrounds of people whose work I had long admired.
杜克·艾灵顿小时候避开音乐课，专注于棒球、绘画和素描。
Duke Ellington shunned music lessons as a kid to focus on baseball and painting and drawing.
玛丽亚姆·米尔扎哈尼小时候对数学不感兴趣，梦想成为一名小说家，
Mariam Mirzakhani wasn't interested in math as a girl, dreamed of becoming a novelist,
后来她成为了第一位，也是迄今为止唯一一位获得菲尔兹奖的女性，
and went on to become the first and so far only woman to win the Fields Medal,
这是世界上最负盛名的数学奖项。
the most prestigious prize in the world in math.
文森特·梵高在彻底失败之前，曾从事过五种不同的职业，
Vincent van Gogh had five different careers before flaming out spectacularly,
在他二十多岁的时候，他拿起了一本名为《绘画入门指南》的书。
and in his late 20s picked up a book called The Guide to the ABCs of Drawing.
克劳德·香农是密歇根大学的一名电气工程师，
Claude Shannon was an electrical engineer at the University of Michigan
他只是为了满足学分要求才选修了一门哲学课。
who took a philosophy course just to fulfill a requirement.
在这门课上，他了解了一个近百年前的逻辑系统，
And in it, he learned about a near-century-old system of logic
通过这个系统，真假陈述可以被编码为一和零，并像数学问题一样被解决。
by which true and false statements could be coded as ones and zeros and solved, like math problems.
这导致了二进制代码的发展，它构成了我们今天所有数字计算机的基础。
This led to the development of binary code, which underlies all of our digital computers today.
弗朗西丝·赫塞尔贝因在54岁时才找到她的第一份专业工作，
Frances Hesselbein took her first professional job at the age of 54,
后来成为了女童子军的首席执行官。
and went on to become the CEO of the Girl Scouts.
这是我关注的一位运动员。
Here's an athlete I've followed.
他尝试过网球、滑雪、摔跤。
He tried some tennis, some skiing, wrestling.
他的母亲实际上是一名网球教练，但她拒绝执教他，
His mother was actually a tennis coach, but she declined to coach him
因为他击球的方式不正常。
because he wouldn't return balls normally.
他继续尝试更多运动。
And he kept trying more sports.
手球、排球、足球、羽毛球、滑板。
So, who is this dabbler?
那么，这个业余爱好者是谁呢？
This is Roger Federer.
这是罗杰·费德勒。
Every bit as famous as an adult as Tiger Woods,
他成年后和泰格·伍兹一样出名，
and yet even tennis enthusiasts,
然而，即使是网球爱好者，
don't usually know anything about his developmental story.
通常也不知道他的成长故事。
Why is that?
这是为什么呢？
Well, I think it's partly because the Tiger story is very dramatic,
嗯，我认为部分原因是泰格的故事非常戏剧性，
but also because it seems like this tidy narrative
但也因为这似乎是一个整洁的叙事，
that we can extrapolate to anything that we want to be good at in our own lives.
我们可以将其推广到我们生活中任何想擅长的事情上。
But it turns out that in many ways, golf is a uniquely horrible model
但事实证明，在很多方面，高尔夫是一个独特的糟糕模型，
of almost everything that humans want to learn.
几乎是人类想学习的一切的糟糕模型。
Golf is the epitome of what the psychologist Robin Hogarth called a kind learning environment.
高尔夫是心理学家罗宾·霍加斯所说的“友善学习环境”的缩影。
Next steps and goals are clear, rules are clear, and never change.
下一步和目标明确，规则明确，永不改变。
When you do something, you get feedback that is quick and accurate.
当你做某事时，你会得到快速准确的反馈。
Chess, also a kind learning environment.
国际象棋，也是一个友善的学习环境。
On the other end of the spectrum are wicked learning environments,
光谱的另一端是“险恶学习环境”，
where next steps and goals may not be clear.
在那里，下一步和目标可能不明确。
Rules may change.
规则可能会改变。
You may or may not get feedback when you do something.
当你做某事时，你可能会或可能不会得到反馈。
It may be delayed. It may be inaccurate.
它可能延迟。它可能不准确。
Which one of these sounds like the world we're increasingly living in?
这听起来像我们日益生活的世界吗？
So, if hyperspecialization isn't always the trick in a wicked world, what is?
那么，如果超专业化在险恶世界中并非总是诀窍，那是什么呢？
That can be difficult to talk about,
这可能很难谈论，
because sometimes it looks like meandering or zigzagging or keeping a broader view.
因为有时它看起来像是漫无目的、曲折前进或保持更广阔的视野。
It can look like getting behind.
它可能看起来像落后了。
But if we look at research on technological innovation,
但如果我们看看技术创新的研究，
it shows that increasingly, the most impactful patents are authored by teams
它表明，最具影响力的专利越来越多地由团队撰写，
that include individuals who have worked across a large number of different technology classes
这些团队包括在大量不同技术类别中工作过的个人，
and often merged things from different domains.
并且经常融合来自不同领域的事物。
Someone whose work I've admired who is sort of on the forefront of this,
我钦佩的一位在这方面处于前沿的人，
a Japanese man named Gunpei Yokoi.
是一位名叫横井军平的日本人。
Yokoi didn't score well in his electronics exams at school,
横井在学校的电子考试中成绩不佳，
so he had to settle for a low-tier job as a machine maintenance worker
所以他不得不满足于在京都一家扑克牌公司做一名低级机械维修工。
at a playing card company in Kyoto.
他将计算器行业的一些知名技术，
He combined some well-known technology from the calculator industry
与信用卡行业的一些知名技术结合起来，
with some well-known technology from the credit card industry
制造了掌上游戏机。
and made handheld games.
这使这家在19世纪一个木制店面创立的扑克牌公司，
And it turned this playing card company,
变成了一家玩具和游戏公司。
which was founded in a wooden storefront in the 19th century,
你可能听说过它。它叫任天堂。
into a toy and game operation.
他的代表作是Game Boy。
You may have heard of it. It's called Nintendo.
我们可能没有培养出尽可能多的那样的人，
His magnum opus was the Game Boy.
因为我们不倾向于奖励任何
We probably don't make as many of those people as we could,
看起来不像领先或专业化的东西。
because we don't tend to incentivize anything
当然，我认为成功的途径和人一样多。
that doesn't look like a head start or specialization.
但我认为我们往往只奖励和鼓励“老虎之路”，
And naturally, I think there are as many ways to succeed as there are people.
然而在一个日益险恶的世界中，
But I think we tend only to incentivize and encourage the tiger path,
我们也需要走“罗杰之路”的人。
when increasingly in a wicked world,
或者正如杰出的物理学家、数学家和作家所说，
Freeman Dyson, put it,
弗里曼·戴森曾说，
for a healthy ecosystem, we need both birds and frogs.
对于健康的生态系统，我们需要鸟和青蛙。
Frogs are down in the mud seeing all the granular details.
青蛙在泥泞中，看到所有细枝末节。
The birds are soaring up above not seeing those details,
鸟儿在高空翱翔，看不到那些细节，
but integrating the knowledge of the frogs.
但它们整合了青蛙的知识。
And we need both.
我们两者都需要。
The problem, Dyson said,
戴森说，问题在于，
is that we're telling everyone to become frogs.
我们在告诉所有人成为青蛙。
And I think, in a wicked world,
我认为，在一个险恶的世界里，
that's increasingly short-sighted.
这会越来越短视。
Education is the ultimate idea worth spreading.
教育是最终值得传播的理念。
That's why we have a channel dedicated exclusively
这就是为什么我们有一个专门的频道，
to celebrating and elevating the ideas of educators.
用来颂扬和提升教育者的思想。
Visit our Educator Talks channel,
访问我们的“教育者演讲”频道，
where you can also learn more about our educator programs.
在那里你还可以了解更多关于我们的教育者项目。
Or watch the unabbreviated version of this talk here.
或者在这里观看本次演讲的完整版。